A Guide to the Danville (Va.) Civil Rights Case Files, 1963-1973
Library of Virginia
- Dictabelts (38099-1 - 38099-39)
  - David Adams, et. als. 14 February 1967 (Belts 1-6), Total time: 2 hours, 10 minutes, 4 seconds (38099-21 and 38099-22)
    - Recording file 2k204-114 14 February 1967, Ralph McDonald Hairston testimony (continued)/ Defense rests/ James A. H. Ferguson (Danville City Attorney) testimony/ Re-direct/ Prosecution motion for a bench warrant to be issued for the arrest of Edgar Lee Via on a charge of perjury/ Prosecution and Defense rests/ Defense motion to dismiss/ Judge's ruling and sentences/ [28:09] (38099-22)
    - Recording file 2k204-115 14 February 1967, Judge's ruling and sentences (continued)/ [2:09] (38099-22)
  - Mabel Elizabeth Bethel, et. als. 14 February 1967 (Belts 1-2), Total time: 44 minutes, 54 seconds (38099-23)
    - Recording file 2k204-116 14 February 1967, Recorder sworn/ Cases consolidated/ Defense motions/ Lonnie Riddle (police officer) testimony/ Defense motion in re: double jeopardy/ Lonnie Riddle testimony (continued)/ Re-direct/ Re-cross/ Re-re-direct, etc. (5x)/ [30:00] (38099-23)
    - Recording file 2k204-117 14 February 1967, Prosecution rests/ Defense closing argument/ Prosecution closing argument/ Judge's ruling and sentences/ Defense motion to suspend sentences pending appeal/ [14:54] (38099-23)
  - Mary MacAglean Davis, et. als. 14 February 1967 (Belt 1), Total time: 23 minutes, 52 seconds (38099-24)
    - Recording file 2k204-118 14 February 1967, Recorder sworn/ Prosecution requests postponement/ Judge grants postponement/ Remaining cases consolidated/ Defense motions stipulated/ Lonnie Riddle (police officer) testimony/ Re-direct/ Defense motions to strike evidence and witness testimony and in re: double jeopardy/ Defense rests/ Judge's ruling and sentences/ Defense motion to suspend sentences pending appeal/ Recess/ [23:52] (38099-24)
  - Gloria Jane Barton, et. als. 15 February 1967 (Belt 1), Total time: 50 minutes, 53 seconds (38099-25)
    - Recording file 2k204-032 15 February 1967, Recorder sworn/ Cases consolidated/ Defense motions stipulated/ Eugene G. McCain (chief of police) testimony/ G. W. Platt (general merchandise manager at Belk-Leggett Company) testimony/ L. P. Rigney (police officer) testimony/ Re-direct/ W. L. Buettner (police officer) testimony/ Re-direct/ Re-cross/ [31:26] (38099-25)
    - Recording file 2k204-033 15 February 1967, L. A. Howerton (police officer) testimony/ H. R. Chaney (police officer) testimony/ Prosecution rests/ Defense motions renewed/ Defense rests/ Judge's ruling and sentences/ Defense motion to suspend sentences pending appeal/ [19:26] (38099-25)
  - Evelyn Holt Beavers, et. als. 15 February 1967 (Belts 1-2), Total time: 41 minutes, 4 seconds (38099-26)
    - Recording file 2k204-034 15 February 1967, Recorder sworn/ Cases consolidated/ Lonnie Riddle (police officer) testimony/ Re-direct/ Re-cross/ Prosecution rests/ Defense motions renewed/ Defense motion to dismiss/ [31:04] (38099-26)
    - Recording file 2k204-035 15 February 1967, Defense motion to dismiss (continued)/ Prosecution argument against motions/ Judge's ruling and sentences/ Defense motion to suspend sentences pending appeal/ [10:00] (38099-26)
  - Maggie Lou Jennings, et. als. 15 February 1967 (Belts 1-2), Total time: 35 minutes, 29 seconds (38099-27)
    - Recording file 2k204-036 15 February 1967, Recorder sworn/ Cases consolidated/ Norman H. Boswell (police officer) testimony/ Juby E. Towler (captain of police) testimony/ [31:19] (38099-27)
    - Recording file 2k204-037 15 February 1967, Prosecution rests/ Defense motions renewed/ Judge's ruling and sentences/ Defense motion to suspend sentences pending appeal/ [4:10] (38099-27)
  - Randy Adams, et. als. 16-20 February 1967 (Belts 1-19), Total time: 8 hours, 21 minutes, 47 seconds (38099-28, 38099-29, 38099-30, 38099-31 and 38099-32)
    - Recording file 2k204-038 16 February 1967, Recorder sworn/ Announcement of Charles Luther Morgan (attorney from Lynchburg for the Defense)/ Cases consolidated/ Defense motions/ Eugene G. McCain (chief of police) testimony/ [30:04] (38099-28)
    - Recording file 2k204-039 16 February 1967, Eugene G. McCain testimony (continued)/ [29:40] (38099-28)
    - Recording file 2k204-040 16 February 1967, Eugene G. McCain testimony (continued)/ [29:39] (38099-28)
    - Recording file 2k204-041 16 February 1967, Eugene G. McCain testimony (continued)/ Recess for lunch/ Reconvene/ Eugene G. McCain testimony (continued)/ Re-direct/ [26:10] (38099-28)
    - Recording file 2k204-042 16 February 1967, Eugene G. McCain testimony (continued)/ Re-cross/ Re-re-direct, etc. (4x)/ Lonnie Riddle (police officer) testimony/ [29:16] (38099-29)
    - Recording file 2k204-043 16 February 1967, Lonnie Riddle testimony (continued)/ Thomas W. Evans (police officer) testimony/ [Recorder took belt off to check machine]/ [15:52] (38099-29)
    - Recording file 2k204-044 16 February 1967, Thomas W. Evans testimony (continued)/ Re-direct/ Re-cross/ Recess/ Reconvene/ Willard Osborne (police officer) testimony/ Re-direct/ Jackson Brown (police officer) testimony/ [29:04] (38099-29)
    - Recording file 2k204-045 16 February 1967, Jackson Brown testimony (continued)/ John W. Martin Jr. (police officer) testimony/ Re-direct/ T. Neal Morris (police officer) testimony/ [29:15] (38099-29)
    - Recording file 2k204-046 16 February 1967, T. Neal Morris testimony (continued)/ Re-direct/ Re-cross/ Re-re-direct/ B. G. Buchanan (police officer) testimony/ Coley Boone (records officer, police officer and photographer) testimony/ Adjournment/ [22:57] (38099-29)
    - Recording file 2k204-047 17 February 1967, Reconvene/ Walter Brown (police officer and photographer) testimony/ Juby E. Towler (police captain) testimony/ [30:28] (38099-30)
    - Recording file 2k204-048 17 February 1967, Juby E. Towler testimony (continued)/ Re-direct/ John M. Bailey (police officer) testimony/ C. W. Howerton (police officer) testimony/ Defense motions renewed/ Defense motions to strike evidence and witness testimony/ Prosecution argument against Defense motions/ Defense argument/ Judge's ruling on motions (overruled)/ Emmett Lee Banks (demonstrator from Chatham) testimony/ [29:33] (38099-30)
    - Recording file 2k204-049 17 February 1967, Emmett Lee Banks testimony (continued)/ Defense motion/ Clyde L. Banks (demonstrator) testimony/ [29:06] (38099-30)
    - Recording file 2k204-050 17 February 1967, Clyde L. Banks testimony (continued)/ Emmett Banks Case dismissed/ Recess/ Eugene G. McCain (chief of police) testimony/ Re-direct/ Lonnie Riddle (police officer) recall testimony/ L. Wilson York (demonstrator) testimony/ [26:08] (38099-30)
    - Recording file 2k204-051 17 February 1967, L. Wilson York testimony (continued)/ Re-direct/ Re-cross/ Othea Davis (demonstrator) testimony/ [29:26] (38099-31)
    - Recording file 2k204-052 17 February 1967, Othea Davis testimony (continued)/ Joseph Hatchett (demonstrator) testimony/ Re-direct/ Re-cross/ Reverend Lawrence Wendell Chase (pastor at High Street Baptist Church) testimony/ [29:09] (38099-31)
    - Recording file 2k204-053 17 February 1967, Reverend Lawrence Wendell Chase testimony (continued)/ Elaine Elizabeth Chase (demonstrator) Case dismissed/ Robert L. Trent (demonstrator) testimony/ Robert L. Trent Case dismissed/ Defense rests/ Defense motions/ Judge's ruling on motions (overruled)/ Prosecution waives opening argument/ Defense argument/ [28:53] (38099-31)
    - Recording file 2k204-054 17 February 1967, Defense argument (continued)/ Prosecution argument/ Judge's ruling and sentences/ Adjournment until Monday/ [21:55] (38099-31)
    - Recording file 2k204-055 20 February 1967, Reconvened/ Docket called/ Judge's ruling and sentences (continued)/ [28:53] (38099-32)
    - Recording file 2k204-056 20 February 1967, Judge's ruling and sentences (continued)/ [6:13] (38099-32)
  - Bruce Baines, et. als. 20 February 1967 (Belt 1), Total time: 1 minute, 11 seconds (38099-33)
    - Recording file 2k204-057 20 February 1967, Prosecution motion to Nolle Pros'd cases numbered 327-335/ Judge grants motion/ Adjournment/ [1:11] (38099-33)
  - James Coleman, et. als. 20 February 1967 (Belts 1-3), Total time: 1 hour, 3 minutes, 22 seconds (38099-34)
    - Recording file 2k204-058 20 February 1967, Recorder sworn/ Cases consolidated/ Defense motions/ Eugene G. McCain (chief of police) testimony/ C. W. Howerton (police officer) testimony/ [29:13] (38099-34)
    - Recording file 2k204-059 20 February 1967, C. W. Howerton testimony (continued)/ Re-direct/ Charles Wade Graff (police officer and photographer) testimony/ Coley Boone (records officer, police officer and photographer) testimony/ Defense motions/ Prosecution argument against motion/ Judge's ruling on motion (overruled)/ Defense rests/ Defense argument/ [29:15] (38099-34)
    - Recording file 2k204-060 20 February 1967, Defense argument (continued)/ Judge's ruling and sentences/ [4:53] (38099-34)
  - Sallie Mae Harper, et. als. 20 February 1967 (Belts 1-2), Total time: 49 minutes, 40 seconds (38099-35)
    - Recording file 2k204-061 20 February 1967, Recorder sworn/ Docket called/ Defense motions stipulated/ T. Neal Morris (police officer) testimony/ Norman H. Boswell (police officer) testimony/ Charles Wade Graff (police officer and photographer) testimony/ [28:24] (38099-35)
    - Recording file 2k204-062 20 February 1967, Charles Wade Graff testimony (continued)/ Prosecution rests/ Defense motions/ Recess/ Reconvene/ Defense argument/ Defense rests/ Defense argument/ Judge's ruling and sentences/ Defense motion to suspend sentences pending appeal/ [21:16] (38099-35)
  - Julius Emanuel Adams, et. als. 21 February 1967 (Belts 1-2), Total time: 44 minutes, 47 seconds (38099-36)
    - Recording file 2k204-063 21 February 1967, Recorder sworn/ Defense motions/ Lonnie Riddle (police officer) testimony/ Re-direct/ L. P. Rigney (police officer) testimony/ Reverend Frances F. McFarland testimony/ Re-direct/ Evelyn Gray McGhee (demonstrator) testimony/ [29:14] (38099-36)
    - Recording file 2k204-064 21 February 1967, Mary Davis testimony (continued)/ Prosecution rests/ Defense motions/ Judge's ruling and sentences/ [15:32] (38099-36)
  - Barbara Caldwell, et. als. 6 April 1967 (Belts 1-3), Total time: 1 hour, 2 minutes, 57 seconds (38099-37)
    - Recording file 2k204-065 6 April 1967, Recorder sworn/ Defense argument/ Prosecution argument/ Defense argument/ [30:00] (38099-37)
    - Recording file 2k204-066 6 April 1967, Defense argument (continued)/ Prosecution argument/ Judge's ruling and sentences/ [30:00] (38099-37)
    - Recording file 2k204-067 6 April 1967, Judge's ruling and sentences (continued)/ [2:57] (38099-37)
  - Connie Lavonne Chaney, et. als. 6 April 1967 (Belt 1), Total time: 5 minutes, 13 seconds (38099-38)
    - Recording file 2k204-068 6 April 1967, Judge's ruling and sentences (continued: from previous case)/ Prosecution motion to Nolle Pros'd cases numbered 354-363/ Judge grants motion/ [5:13] (38099-38)
  - Lawrence George Campbell, A. I. Dunlap, Julius E. Adams, and Arthur Pinchback (suspension of sentence hearing) 9 February 1973 (Belts 1-3), Total time: 1 hour, 16 minutes, 38 seconds (38099-39)
    - Recording file 2k204-069 6 April 1967, Recorder sworn/ Defense motion/ Judge's ruling on motion (denied)/ T. Neal Morris (police officer) testimony/ Re-direct/ Re-cross/ Howard Lee (minister) testimony/ Everette L. Motley (Danville Public Schools) testimony/ Charles H. Harris (bank cashier) testimony/ [30:00] (38099-39)
    - Recording file 2k204-070 6 April 1967, Reverend Samuel Griffith testimony/ M. C. Martin (banker) testimony/ Wesley H. Motley Jr. testimony/ Roger Edwards testimony/ Julian R. Stinson testimony/ Doyle J. Thomas testimony/ Defense rests/ [34:26] (38099-39)
    - Recording file 2k204-071 6 April 1967, Defense argument/ Judge's ruling and sentences/ [12:12] (38099-39)